hi so we're ready for the
third meditation for the third week of
this
long room course and in the last
meditation
we had done an act of truth
to send actually the whole thing we're
trying to send the virus
to the middle of the sun right and i
like to think
if our alarm rim course together
if we are successful together then
something will happen to the virus you
know maybe we can
contribute to stopping this problem in
the world
it should be like that right so let's
try
okay and we did an act of truth
act of truth requires some ammunition
act of truth is like shooting a gun
right
and you need some kind of ammunition you
you have to say
if it's true i did this then may this
happen
and uh we we said
if it's true that i've shown any small
kindnesses okay i i've been reading
articles about someone who served the
hundred thousand meals
in hospitals hooked up all the
restaurants to the hospitals
and served a hundred thousand meals and
i i read another article about
the five physicians from from my old
university
and they're just doing extraordinary
things you know huge
things that affect thousands and
thousands of people but
people like you and me you know during
this virus
not to go along with the general fear
not to go along with the general self
self-preservation instinct not to go out
and buy all the toilet paper
on the first day of the virus you know
uh
try to do small things for other people
okay that's our ammunition okay so i
guess that means if you haven't done any
small things
for other people during this virus then
let's get started
all right so just small good things you
know
encourage other people give other people
some hope
share things with other people you don't
have to
i read about a lady who made 30 000 mass
or something okay yeah i'm not talking
about that i'm talking about
identifying people who are scared
and who are sad and who are worried
about the future
and showing them some basic human
kindness okay
uh so that was our ammunition
and then we did an act of truth if it's
true
that during the days of the virus during
the time of the
of the virus i did this a nice thing to
someone else small
small elegant nice thing then
uh you know blind people should start to
see
and hungry people should be given a
great meal
and sick people should get better people
on ventilators should all start
breathing on their own
and even people who are traveling in
their cars because they can't go in a
plane
they should be safe their car should
work nice
children should be safe during this
difficult time
elderly people should be safe during
this difficult time people have
trouble sleeping which is i don't know i
haven't seen any numbers but it's got to
be a huge problem right now
then then we did an act of truth
and we sent that to those people
now we're gonna do another act of truth
okay this is the third meditation
and we're shifting gears okay we're
still in the human realm
okay we're still in the world of human
beings we got out of the hell realms
animal realms
hungry ghost realms and we're still
dealing
with troubles in this world
during this virus shanti deva makes a
list okay
so remember where we are we're going to
do this meditation now
we're going to do an act of truth we're
going to think about
some small beautiful elegant
package of kindness we have delivered
during this
virus and we're gonna make a mental
statement
that if it's true that i have done this
small kind thing
then may may the following things happen
and then there'll be a list of things
that we want to happen
so here we go get ready to meditate
okay take a drink of water
and these meditations are short they're
they're designed to be 15 minutes only
something to do once or twice a day
so we're going to make it very simple
we're going to get into the meditation
with 10 breaths
here we go long exhales
keep exhaling until the lower tummy
tightens which is more than you usually
exhale
we're gonna do 10 long breaths this week
long and fine
now please think about some small
elegant beautiful kindness you have
paid to someone during this
difficult time in the whole world
who's afraid worried about the future
and some small gesture you made to them
but it should be
real it should be something you really
do
and then say to yourself let's do an act
of truth
if it's true that during this
frightening time
i paid one small kindness
to another person
then the following things should happen
okay and here's our list
from the master shanty davis
chapter on dedication number one
people who are having obstacles
with their spiritual practice right
these are deeper deeper obstacles
than not having food or not having
clothing okay
at the beginning of this meditation
session we showed a photograph
of a young woman meditating and and
people were making fun of her
so if it's true that i have paid some
kindness
and made obstacles to people's faith
and wisdom and love may these
obstacles to their spiritual life be
removed
in this world
if it's true that i did this one kind
thing
during this difficult time
then may everyone everywhere
and it's humans everywhere in the
universe may they have the freedom
to practice their own spiritual path
may they have this freedom may they be
free from interference in their private
spiritual life
and may they be free from
divisiveness inside of spiritual
practitioners
may they have enjoy
some kind of unity and harmony
within groups of spiritual practitioners
and
in general may they have the freedom to
follow the path
they would like to try
here shantideva adds another group of
people
these are people who have not been able
to practice
well because of physical
needs they they didn't have enough food
they didn't have enough money they
didn't have sufficient clothing and it
actually damaged their body
and that damage to their body also
damaged their self-esteem
so if it's true i have
paid this kindness to someone else
then by this act of truth
may people like that
with with low self-esteem may they come
to have
great spiritual practice
and shantideva here includes people who
were born into a society which has
different levels within that society
and among those levels they were born
into the lower levels
and they were taken advantage of
or they were hurt systematically by the
system
of their of their culture
and they were kept down may those people
suddenly find the right
and the position to enjoy a deep
spiritual practice
and by the way i will take away the
seeds
of bad thoughts words and deeds done by
any of these people in the past okay
that's similar to taking away illness
from a person
illness is what we call result suffering
and the seeds for that are are negative
being negative
in how you speak how you think how you
act
so may this act of truth
also removes suffering in the form of
pain which is about to come things which
are not pain yet
pain which is waiting to happen
if i've done this act of truth may
people show
loving conduct to each other may there
be no
darkness in their attitude or their
behavior
may they be perfectly innocent
and helpful and kind to each other
may all spiritual practitioners through
my act of truth
live a long life
may they feel experiences of bliss
and then shanti deva ends this
meditation very sweetly
may the word death disappear from this
world
may we come to a time in this world
where nobody knows what the word virus
means
and nobody remembers what the word coven
and no one even remembers what the word
death used to mean
because these things are gone if it's
true i've been
shown some kindness during this pandemic
then
made these things come to pass
then slowly open your eyes
take a good drink
and we'll do this meditation for a week
and then we'll pick up
with master deva next week
thank you thanks tim thanks sadie